Dylan Albertazzi

Corvallis, OR 97330 • (541)678-2132 D.Albertazzi10@gmail.com www.linkedIn.com/in/DAlbertazzi Website: DylanAlbertazzi.com

Cloud Solutions Architect

Software Development / Cloud Technologies / Business Development

Proven experience using technology to increase the profitability of businesses. Over 6 years of coding experience with a heavy focus on web and cloud technologies. Possess great leadership skills and a team-first mentality. Diverse background in technical and creative work with demonstrated ability in bringing both together to reach the goals and increase revenue for clients.

Areas of Expertise:

Software Development, Self-Initiative, Realization of Client Goals, Collaboration

- AWS Solutions Architect Associate Certification
- AWS Cloud Practitioner Certification
- Client and Results Oriented
- Effective Verbal and Written Communication skills, including Presentations.

Professional Experience

Albertazzi Law Firm • Bend, OR

Jun. 2018 - present

Web Development and SEO

Built website and implemented SEO strategy.

Dylan's website and search engine optimization strategy generated new business leads that attracted enough clients to minimize the need for paid referrals, saving the firm an estimated 12% in annual referral expenses. Demonstrated abilities for user interface design, high care for user experience, and partnership in the long-term vision of the firm.

Contributions:

- 57% increase in new clients retained from the internet.
- Over \$115,000 in **increased** profits as a direct result of clients obtained from the new website and SEO campaign.

Variance - New York City, NY

Oct. 2020 - Dec. 2020

Software Engineering Intern - (Remote)

Improved customer experience by inspecting patterns in the code of many popular applications to map them to the Variance software. Provided insight to improve the product. Learned from a world-class team comprised of the founders of Percolate.

Application Experience

GrubGuide • Bend, OR

Aug. 2020 - present

Cloud Application Development

Single-handedly built GrubGuide.

Personal Project. Restaurant suggestion app built on AWS, with a serverless architecture. See GrubGuide.io and the "Architecting GrubGuide" article in the blog section of Dylan's website for more details.

...continued...

OSU Global Formula Racing • Corvallis, OR

Aug. 2020 - present

Senior Project Built on AWS

Led the team making data visualization tool.

The tool is designed on AWS for OSU's Global Formula Racing Team. Architected a solution for the AWS cloud.

Volunteer Experience

Young Life • Corvallis, OR

Sep. 2016 – Feb. 2018

Organizer and Mentor

1500+ unpaid hours of volunteer work.

Mentored 12 middle schoolers weekly. Responsible for a team of 10 college leaders, which involved scheduling, training, planning, and conducting weekly meetings. Coordinated with leaders, community, and parents to put on bi-monthly events with the middle schoolers.

DRL Robotics Lab • Corvallis, OR

Sep. 2019 - Jan. 2020

Research Assistant

Undergraduate research for the most well-known lab on campus. Consistently completing time-sensitive projects and collaborating with other members through GitHub, debugging other's code, etc. See my website for my work with the lab.

Shared Technologies • Portland, OR

May. 2019 - Sept. 2019

Intern

Delivered a product-market fit analysis ahead of new market entry, flagging markets with the highest profit margins for Shared's operational model. Led out customer discovery efforts across 30 US cities. Consulted at the executive level regarding all customer discovery and market entry initiatives.

Skills

- AWS EC2, Lambda, S3, RDS, VPC, IAM, Amplify, Billing, CloudWatch, among others
- JavaScript, Node, React, MongoDB, SQL, Python, C++, GitHub, HTML/CSS
- AWS Management Console, VS Code, Slack, Notion, GSuite, Figma, Office 365, Adobe Creative Suite

About

Spends free time reading, running, skiing, spending time with family and friends, and creating YouTube videos about technology that enables business.

Education

BS, Mechanical Engineering, Minor Computer Science • Oregon State University – Corvallis, OR

Graduated Mar. 2021, 3.54/4.0 GPA

Honors Diploma • Summit High School – Bend, OR

Graduated Jun. 2016, 3.75/4.0 GPA. Senior Class Representative. 3-time first-team all-conference, baseball.